Curriculum Vitae Ega Kurnia Yazid

New York City, USA

Contact

Email: e.yazid@columbia.edu

Phone:

Website: kurniayazid.github.io

Information

yazidega@gmail.com +1 (347) 794-2704

Linkedin: linkedin.com/in/kurniayazid/ Github: github.com/kurniayazid

Professional Summary

Ega (he/him) is a final year Master's student in Quantitative Methods in the Social Sciences (QMSS) at Columbia University, fully funded by the Indonesia Endowment Fund for Education (LPDP) scholarship. While studying, he also manages as a Graduate Research Assistant at Columbia University Mailman School of Public Health as well as a Teaching Assistant at Barnard College (BC).

Prior to this, he worked as a Research Assistant at the Department of Economics and a Research Fellow at the Disaster Management Research Unit (DMRU) Centre for Strategic and International Studies (CSIS). At CSIS, he actively participated in writing analytical reports on various topics such as development economics, disaster economics, and policy analysis. Additionally, he assisted the Senior Advisor for poverty eradication to the Minister of National Development Planning in the Republic of Indonesia, specifically in producing evidence-based recommendations.

His work involved undertaking various economic, business, and investment research projects, ranging from the gig economy to renewable energy investments. His research areas of interest include development economics, environmental economics, health economics, disaster management, and digital economy. He earned his bachelor's degree in economics from Universitas Gadjah Mada, Indonesia, in 2019.

Education

Master of Arts, Quantitative Methods in the Social Sciences Sep 2022 - Dec 2023Columbia University, New York City, USA. GPA 3.77/4.00

Aug 2015 - Jun 2019

Universitas Gadjah Mada, Yogyakarta, Indonesia. GPA 3.63/4.00

Certification

Evaluation of social programs

Bachelor of Science, Economics

Jul 2022

JPAL-SEA

Data Science Professional Certificate

Mar 2020

IBM

Certification ID: EAZ88LMHANAE

Teaching Experience TA: Environmental Data Analysis (BC3017) Barnard College, New York City, USA

Spring 2023

Professional Experiences

South China Sea Data Initiative

Role: Part-time Research Assistant

• Collecting and recoding South China Sea major events data.

Columbia University Mailman School of Public Health Aug 2023 – Dec 2023 Role: Graduate Research Assistant

- Evaluating and preparing cleaned survey data on People with HIV NYC CHAIN Data
- Performing survival analysis to explore socioeconomic factors affecting aging for People with HIV

Ministry of National Development Planning, Indonesia

Jun 2020 – Aug 2022

Role: Socioeconomic Modelling Specialist / Consultant

Assisted the Senior Advisor to the Minister for Social Affairs and Poverty Eradication to prepare the policy briefs and advice regarding socioeconomic issues and policies.

Centre for Strategic and International Studies (CSIS)

Jan 2020 – Jul 2022

Role: Research Fellow at DMRU & Research Assistant at Department of Economics

- Conducted research and provided economic as well as statistical analysis
- Prepared the academic papers and policy memo for the policy discussion
- Involved in departmental and unit projects from brainstorming for the research proposal to reporting the research results and evaluation

Tenggara Strategics

Feb 2020 - Dec 2020

Nov 2023 - Present

Role: Economic Researcher

- Estimated the leading ride-hailing service provider's economic contribution. Directly shared the report with Grab's Indonesia Board of Directors.
- Wrote daily media monitoring on the current national affairs for both national and international clients.

Work in Progress

"Local Government Environmental Budget Performance on Air Pollution in Indonesia: Evidence from Near Real-Time Satellite Data", written with Kelvin Ramadhan and Muhammad Faiz Zaidan Alharkan, presented at The 11th Congress of the Asian Association of Environmental and Resource Economics (AAERE), 2022

"Shooting the Wrong Target: Estimating the Opportunity Loss from Inclusion Errors in Social Assistance Program", written with Herman Palani, presented at The 17th Indonesian Regional Science Association (IRSA) International Conference, 2022

Publications & Research Projects

"Fight Against Death Tolls and Economic Slowdown: Striking a Balance Between Mobility and Vaccination", 2022, with Herman Palani, published in CSIS Research Report.

"G20 Toolkit for Measuring Digital Skills and Digital Literacy", 2022, published in collaboration with Oxford Digital Pathways, SMERU Institute, and Ministry of ICT Indonesia.

"Mapping The Wellbeing and Regeneration of Fisher Community", 2021, with Prof. Arief Anshory Yusuf, Prof. Nur Iriawan, Vivi Yulaswati, and Herman Palani, published at Bulletin of Statistics Community Forum (FMS)

"Tracking the Ups and Downs in Indonesia's Economic Activity During COVID-19 Using Mobility Index: Evidence from Provinces in Java and Bali", 2021, with Yose Rizal Damuri, Prabaning Tyas, Haryo Aswicahyono, Lionel Priyadi, and Stella Kusumawardhani, published in ERIA Discussion Paper Series.

"Bouncing Back: An Empirical Evidence of Aggregate Economic Impact of Disasters in Indonesia", 2021, with Esa Azali Asyahid, published in CSIS Working Paper.

"Exploration of the Relationship between COVID-19 Cases and Google Search Trends in Indonesia", 2021, with Haryo Aswicahyono, published in CSIS Working Paper.

"Readiness of Greater Jakarta hospitals key in mitigating the spread of COVID-19", 2020, with Mikhail Gorbachev Dom, published on The Jakarta Post.

"Game Theory Behind the Dilemma of Homecoming Eid amid the COVID-19 Pandemic", 2020, with Fadli Jihad Dahana Setiawan, published in CSIS Commentaries.

Computer & Programming Skills

Data Analysis Software: STATA, Python, R, Eviews, QGIS

Data Management: SQL, IBM Cloud Research Reporting: Ms Office, LATEX

Collaborative Ecosystem: Microsoft-Teams, Google-Suite, GitHub

Awards & Scholarship (Selected)

- 1. Scholarship Awardee Indonesia Endowment Fund for Education (LPDP)
- 2. 2nd Winner HackData (Hackathon + Datathon), Indosat Ooredo (2019)
- 3. 1st Winner Indonesia Economic Outlook'19, University of Indonesia (2018)
- 4. 1st Winner Taxplore Paper Competition, University of Indonesia (2018)

References

Please let me know before contacting the referee(s)

Dr. Vivi Yulaswati

Deputy Minister for Maritime & National Resources Ministry of National Development Planning, Republic of Indonesia viviyulaswati@bappenas.go.id

Dr. Gumilang Sahadewo

Vice Dean of the Faculty of Economics and Business Universitas Gadjah Mada gasahadewo@ugm.ac.id